恭喜你学会了扩散模型的基础知识。
Congratulations on learning about the foundations of diffusion models.
现在把所有内容整合在一起，你已经能够训练扩散模型来预测噪声，
Now putting it all together, you're able to train a diffusion model to predict noise,
并迭代地从纯噪声中减去预测的噪声，得到一幅好的图像。
and iteratively subtract the predicted noise from pure noise to get a good image.
你可以从训练好的神经网络中快速采样图像，使用更高效的采样器DDIM。
You're able to sample images from that trained neural network, fast too with a more efficient sampler called DDIM.
你了解了模型结构，一个单元。
You went through the model architecture, a unit.
你将上下文融入模型，以便你可以选择想要的食物、魔法、英雄形象，或者介于两者之间的有趣事物。
You put context into the model so that you could decide whether you wanted food or spells or a hero sprite out, or something quirky in between.
最后，你探索并运行了所有这些代码。
Finally, you explored and ran the code for all of this.
现在你可以创建自己的数据集，尝试生成新的东西。
Now you can create your own dataset and try to generate new things.
扩散模型并不仅限于图像，只是它们在这方面最受欢迎。
Diffusion models aren't bound to images either, that's just where they've been the most popular.
还有用于音乐的扩散模型，你可以给它任何提示，然后得到音乐，还可以提议新的分子来加速药物发现。
There are diffusion models for music, where you can give it any prompt and get music out, for proposing new molecules to accelerate drug discovery.
你也可以尝试更大的数据集，尝试一个新的采样器。
You can also try a larger dataset, try a new sampler.
实际上有很多比DDIM更快更好的。
There are actually a ton out there that are even faster and better than DDIM.
你可以用这些模型做更多事情，比如图像修复，让扩散模型在你已有的图像周围绘制一些东西。
You can do more with these models, such as inpainting, which is letting the diffusion model paint something around an existing image you already have.
还有文本反演，它可以让模型通过几个样本图像捕捉到全新的文本概念。
And textual inversion, which enables the model to capture an entirely new text concept with just a few sample images.
你已经掌握了基础知识，这是基础。
You covered the basics here, the foundations.
这个领域还有其他重要的发展。
There are other important developments in this space.
例如，Stable Diffusion采用一种名为潜在扩散的方法，它直接在图像嵌入上操作，而不是在图像上操作，使过程更加高效。
For example, Stable Diffusion uses a method called latent diffusion, which operates on image embeddings instead of images directly to make the process even more efficient.
其他值得一提的酷炫方法还有交叉注意力文本调节和无分类器引导。
Other cool methods to call out are cross-attention text conditioning and classifier-free guidance.
研究界还在研究更快的采样方法，因为它在推理时仍然比其他生成模型慢。
And the research community is still working on faster sampling methods because it's still slower than other generative models at inference time.
总的来说，对于扩散模型和整个生成模型来说，这是一个非常激动人心的时期，因为它们在改进，并且应用越来越广泛。
All in all, this is an extremely exciting time for diffusion models and generative models as a whole, as they improve and their applications become ever more widespread.
非常感谢你参加这门课程，期待看到你的作品。
Thank you so much for joining me in this course, and I look forward to seeing what you build.